Contact

yvette_grijalva@yahoo.com

www.linkedin.com/in/yvettegrijalva-msn-fnp-c-aprn-cmsrnab340085 (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

Nursing

Hospitals

Healthcare

Certifications

Duolingo Spanish Fluency: 45% proficient

Certified Medical-Surgical Registered Nurse

Pediatric Advanced Life Support (PALS)

Advanced Cardiac Life Support (ACLS)

Yvette Grijalva, MSN, FNP-C, APRN, CMSRN

FNP-C New graduate

Flagstaff, Arizona Area

Summary

FNP-C new graduate with ten years of acute care as a Registered Nurse with a demonstrated history of working in the hospital & health care industry. Skilled in Emergency Medicine, Advanced Cardiac Life Support (ACLS), Critical Care, Pediatric Advanced Life Support (PALS), and Employee Occupational Health.

Experience

Riverside Health System

2 years 7 months

Emergency Department RN
December 2018 - April 2020 (1 year 5 months)

Williamsburg, VA

Duties included for all age groups: triage, prioritization, assessments, treatments, medications, education, and discharge.

EOH Nurse Manager

October 2017 - May 2019 (1 year 8 months)

Newport News, VA

Assesses, plans, develops, implements and manages Employee Health and worker's comp programs to provide high quality and cost-effective services to volunteers, employees, and physicians in the supported region. Provides employee health screenings and services so that the employees' health status is effectively monitored and maintained. Assesses employee injuries and illnesses to select appropriate interventions. Provides and oversees team members who provide annual screenings for all employees in region to include TB Screening and Fit Testing as required. Work with legal agencies and provide legal testimonies as needed. Responsible for assuring safe practices as referenced in the National Patient Safety Goals, and support safe practice as recommended by the National Quality Forum. Seek out and recognize occupational hazards and provides recommendations. Provide reports to leaders on compliance, maintains and updates OSHA logs.

University of Maryland Charles Regional Medical Center Emergency Room Clinical Nurse II June 2016 - September 2017 (1 year 4 months) La Plata, MD

07/2017 - At UMCRMC as an Emergency Department staff nurse my responsibilities included for all age groups: assessments, treatments, medications, education, and discharge.

06/2016-06/2017 - As Staff Float Pool utilizing the nursing process in providing patient care and patient/family teaching. Organize and implement safe, therapeutic, and efficient patient care. Perform patient assessments, plan nursing care, educate patients, and provide age specific care (neonate through adult-geriatric). Additionally, adhering to AIDET's principles allows for better patient satisfaction, and helps maintain a safe and therapeutic environment of caring for my patients.

Genesis

Assistant Director of Nursing December 2015 - June 2017 (1 year 7 months) La Plata, MD

- * Working at a professional nursing level using both administrative leadership and clinical expertise in order to assure that comprehensive care and treatment is provided to our residents
- * Collaboration with the interdisciplinary team, personalize assessments and goals to address the needs of our residents and their families

College of Southern Maryland Adjunct Faculty (contract) January 2017 - May 2017 (5 months) La Plata, Maryland

Skills Lab for Health Science Nursing Care of Adults. Assisting students to incorporate the nursing process from intellectual to practice for the adult patient in an acute care setting.

MedStar St. Mary's Hospital
Emergency Room RN
March 2015 - December 2015 (10 months)
Page 2 of 4

Leonardtown, MD

As a staff RN in the ER, my job is to plan, implement, and evaluate the nursing care of patients while maintaining appropriate documentation. This involves working in collaboration with the patient, their family, and the health care team, while following evidence based policies and procedures.

Centura Health

4 years 3 months

Emergency Room RN

October 2012 - December 2013 (1 year 3 months)

Colorado Springs, Colorado Area

Emergency Department RN for Penrose-St. Francis Health Services, a full-service, 522-bed acute care facility in Colorado Springs which includes Penrose Hospital and St. Francis Medical Center.

Provide exceptional nursing care for emergency room patients of all ages at a Level IV Trauma Center with 22 emergency room beds and three trauma bays. Responsible for facilitating, communicating, and collaborating with both the healthcare team, and the patient/family to identify and meet the total needs of the patient. Demonstrates personal accountability for relationship-based care, organization mission, and core values while promoting health and safety for each patient.

Penrose-St. Francis has been named one of "America's 50 Best Hospitals" for 6 years in a row (2008 - 2013) by HealthGrades, the only recipient in Colorado. We are part of Centura Health, Colorado and western Kansas' largest hospital and health care network delivering advanced care to more than half a million people each year, across 15 hospitals, seven senior living communities, medical clinics, Flight For Life® and home care and hospice services.

Registered Nurse

October 2009 - October 2012 (3 years 1 month)

Highly motivated goal oriented professional nurse who maintained the highest standards of nursing care for a diverse population of patients on a 30-bed unit of a renal/diabetic/medical floor. As Charge nurse, managed the needs of a 30-bed unit, directing and assisting the staff, represented the floor to numerous committees, reported directly to the clinical manager. As a staff nurse, delegated care to certified nursing assistants through clear and concise communication. Acted as a preceptor to new RNs. Managed the care for 4-7 stable to acutely ill renal, diabetic, and general medical patients. Collaborated care with the healthcare team addressing patient's needs and goals

Education

Herzing University

Post Masters Certificate, Family Nurse Practitioner · (2018 - 2019)

Chamberlain College of Nursing

Master of Science Nursing, Education · (2014 - 2017)

American Sentinel University

Bachelor's of Science Nursing (BSN), Registered Nursing/Registered Nurse \cdot (2011 - 2012)

Colorado Technical University

Associate of Science (AS), Registered Nursing/Registered Nurse · (2007 - 2009)